Guide to the Veterinary Ephemera Collection, 1826-1970
Veterinary Ephemera Collection, 1826-1970
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Veterinary Ephemera Collection, 1826-1970
6610
6.0 cubic ft.
Newspaper clippings, pamphlets, posters, broadsides, maps, photographs, and other ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Newspaper clippings, pamphlets, posters, broadsides, maps, photographs, and other ephemera relating to Veterinary Medicine.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Newspaper clippings, pamphlets, posters, broadsides, maps, photographs, and other ephemera relating to Veterinary Medicine. The collection consists of various materials collected by the Flower Sprecher Veterinary Library over several decades.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Veterinary Medicine.; Veterinarians.
Form and Genre Terms:
Pamphlets; Broadsides; Posters; Maps; Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Transferred from the Flower Sprecher Veterinary Library in 2004
SERIES LIST
Series I. Veterinary and Associated Organizations
Series II. Diseases
Series III. Veterinary Legislation and Regulations
Series IV. Government Miscellanea
Series V. Miscellaneous Veterinary Subjects
Series VI. Audiovisual Material and Graphics
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Veterinary and Associated Organizations
  - 12th International Veterinary Congress, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 14th International Veterinary Congress, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 17th International Veterinary Congress, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association - Conference Programs, 1903-1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association - Conference Programs, 1937-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association - Contributions to Biomedical Research, an AVMA Council on Research Project, Binder 1, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association - Contributions to Biomedical Research, an AVMA Council on Research Project, Binder 2, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Association of Lab Animal Practitioners (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Veterinary Medical Colleges (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conferencia Interamericana de Agricultura, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Delahanty Institute - "Medical and Physical Requirements for Inspector of Foods", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - FAO/WHO Meetings on Veterinary Education, folder 1, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - FAO/WHO Meetings on Veterinary Education, folder 2, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - FAO/WHO Meetings on Veterinary Education, folder 3, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Horse Association of America - Annual Reports, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Horse Association of America - Newsletters, 1924-1934, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Horse Association of America - Leaflets, by number, ca. 1924-1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Horse Association of America - Misc. Pamphlets, ca. 1924-1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Horse Association of America - News Clippings, ca. 1924-1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - International Fertility Association (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Medical Society of the State of New York (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New York State Association of Milk Sanitarians (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New York State Dairymen's Association (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Southern Tier Veterinary Medical Association - General (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Southern Tier Veterinary Medical Association - Minutes, 1924-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Southern Tier Veterinary Medical Association - Minutes, 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Livestock Sanitary Association (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - WHO Standard Nomenclature, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Misc State Organizations (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Veterinary Medical Association of New Jersey (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hudson Valley Veterinary Medical Society - Attendance Book, 1915-1976 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Long Island Veterinary Medical Association (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Organizations (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series II. Diseases
  - Brucellosis (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Distemper (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Foot and Mouth Disease - General (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Foot and Mouth Disease - 1902 outbreak - photos of clippings (Box 4)
  - Foot and Mouth Disease - 1902-3 New England outbreak clippings (Box 4)
  - Rabies (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tuberculosis - General (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tuberculosis - General (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Tuberculosis - General (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tuberculosis - U.S. Department of Agriculture Tuberculosis Eradication - Work Summaries, 1918-1933 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Tuberculosis - U.S. Department of Agriculture Tuberculosis Eradication - Work Summaries oversized, 1918-1933 (Box 5)
  - Yellow Fever, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Diseases (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Diagnosis and Remedies
    - Danish Pharmacopoea, 1826 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - George Knapp Notebook, ca. 1879-1900 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Notebook, ca. 1800s (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series III. Veterinary Legislation and Regulations
  - University of the State of New York - Laws, Rules and Information booklets, 1909-1966 (Box 3)
  - University of the State of New York - Registered Veterinarians booklets, 1917-1963 (Box 3)
  - University of the State of New York - Organization and Institutions booklets, 1922-1933 (Box 3)
  - University of the State of New York - Qualifying Certificates booklets, 1927, 1929, 1936 (Box 3)
  - New York Board Exams, 1896-1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New York Board Exams, 1921-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York Board Exams - Guides and Syllabus (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - New York - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Other States - Licensing Regulations, ca. 1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Other States - Board Exams, ca. 1931-1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - United States Public Health Service Exam, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series IV. Government Miscellanea
  - Plum Island - pamphlet, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - United States Army Veterinary Corps (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - United States Army Veterinary Corps - Examinations (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - United States Bureau of Animal Industry - Directory of Inspection Stations, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - United States Bureau of Animal Industry - Applications, 1935, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - United States Bureau of Animal Industry - Accrediting Exams, 1921-1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series V. Miscellaneous Veterinary Subjects
  - Dogs (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dogs - "English Setters at their Best," a Robert Hannon article, ca. 1924 (Box 4)
  - Horses (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Horses -" John Crounse and his Homemeade Horse Remedy Book - To Cure Man and Beast," an article from the Altamont Enterprise, Sept. 23, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Humor / Cartoons (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Instrument Catalog, Hauptner, Berlin, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Veterinary Colleges - Other (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Veterinary Colleges - Other - New York College of Veterinary Surgeons, 1890-1892 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Veterinary Education (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Veterinary History (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Veterinary History - Europe (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Veterinary Profession (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Veterinary Publications (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Noted Non-Cornell Veterinarians - images and bios (Box 4)
  - Noted Non-Cornell Veterinarians - images and bios (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Noted Non-DVM Cornellians - Leonard Pearson (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Noted Non-DVM Cornellians - Theobald Smith (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Vivisection - NY Anti-Vivisection society pamphlet, 1909 (Box 4)
  - Vivisection - ASPCA/antivivisection (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series VI.Audiovisual Material and Graphics
  - Photographs
    - Veterinary Unit, ROTC, Carlisle, PA [may include C.E. DeCamp], July 10, 1922 (Map-case ***)
    - Ambulance Co. No. 3, ROTC, Carlisle, PA [may include C.E. DeCamp], July 10, 1922 (Map-case ***)
    - Group photo, 57th AVMA meeting, Aug 1920 (Map-case ***)
    - Group photo, XIth International Physiologists Congress, Edinburgh [water damaged and torn], July 1923 (Map-case ***)
    - Group photo, 13th International Physiologists Congress, Boston, [water damaged and stuck to glass]; Aug 1929 (Map-case , behind or near, in frame)
  - Posters, Maps and Broadsides
    - State Committee on Tuberculosis and Public Health of the State Charities Aid Association - Notice of 20th Anniversary, 1927 (Box 5)
    - U.S. Bureau of Animal Industry Map of the U.S. showing Boundary Line of the District Infected wits Splenetic or southern Cattle Fever, Jan 1901 (Box 5)
    - U.S. Bureau of Animal Industry Map of the U.S. Showing Boundary Line of the Quarantine for Tick Fever of Cattle, 1930 (Map-case ***)
    - Poster - Representative Veterinarians of New York State, 1920 (Map-case ***)
    - Guidebook with list of names featured in the poster, "Representative Veterinarians of New York State", 1920 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Broadside - New York Dept of Ag Foot and Mouth Disease Quarantine Notice, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Broadside - New York Dept of Ag Foot and Mouth Disease Quarantine Notice, 1914 (Box 5)
  - 33 1/3 record - "The Aged Dog" by William K Riddell and James Rooney, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Universidade de Sao Paulo certificate and pennant, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Certificates, Diplomas, and Licenses (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Veterinary Illustrations, some by C.R. Redwood, n.d. (Map-case ***)
  - Miscellaneous Veterinary Illustrations, some by C.R. Redwood, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Wood and metal engraving blocks (Box 8-10)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 31)